# **DIEGO CASTILLO**

m: With Request info@diegocastillo.io In the heart of Durham, North Carolina

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-driven professional with an established record of technical operations, system and network configuration, and information security success

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established analytical thinking and technical paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts. Success-focused professional with the ability to troubleshoot and resolve various technical issues in a timely manner, carry out the configuration of systems, networks, and services; and effectively administer and execute a wide range of information security-related duties and functions. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as extensive technical expertise.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Networking
- PowerShell Scripting
- Microsoft Exchange
- Employee Training
- Project Management

- Policy and Compliance
- Delegation of Duties
- Information Assurance
- Microsoft 365
- Service Desk and SLAs

- Quality Assurance
- Active Directory
- Technical Support
- Python Scripting
- Incident Response

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

CYCLOTRON, NORTH CAROLINA, OCT 2022 TO PRESENT

#### **Security Engineer**

- Remediation of vulnerabilities and malicious actions via Microsoft Defender.
- Creation of sensitivity labels and DLP (Data loss prevention) policies within Microsoft's purview
- Compliance coordination within SOC2 domain of Microsoft compliance manager
- Governance of roles and identity access management
- Audit of compliance policies and data protection agreements

THREAD, CARY, NORTH CAROLINA, JULY 2021 TO OCT 2022

#### IT Coordinator

- End user support in daily production
- Orchestration onboarding and offboarding policies
- Coordination of supply lines for international communications and production
- Creation of SOPs and KB articles
- Phishing Remediation in a production environment
- Creation of security protocols and a rules
- Orchestration in Azure in onboarding with RBAC
- Microsoft flow integration with Azure of manual procedures

INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR, MAR 2021 – OCT 2022

#### **CROWD SOURCING**

- Review of audio and video transcriptions by checking data for deficiencies; resolving discrepancies by using standard procedures or returning incomplete documents to the team leader for resolution.
- Process images by reviewing data for deficiencies; resolve any discrepancies by reaching out to the team leader for resolution.

DIEGO CASTILLO Page 2

VERASCI, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA, MAY 2017 TO MAR 2021

#### IT ANALYST

• Perform the troubleshooting, diagnosis, and resolution of various technical issues with end-user devices, network, and server infrastructure, as well as carrying out Server Management.

- Orchestrated onboarding policies of new employees, as well as off-boarding in compliance.
  - o Security implementation of MFA, Remote installation of proprietary software
- Designed cloud imaging of sponsor-related devices.
- Deep knowledge of Active Directory and company architecture
  - o Access Control Lists, Group Policy, scripting, and automation.
- Publication of Standard Operating Procedures. (SOPs)
- Established training policies for new layer-1 Information Technology Analysts.
- Delegation of security updates of multiple production servers.
- Ability to translate technical work issues into clear and concise language.
- Deployment of internal communications phones from traditional to VoIP.
- Manage workloads in a complete and timely manner.
- Research and deployment of new server architecture.

VERASCI, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA, MAY 2013 TO JAN 2017

### **Operations Assistant**

- · Logistics of study materials both international and domestic.
- Delegating the creation of study materials for sponsors.
- Distribution of study data and materials to internal personnel from global sites
  - o Gate Keeper for information and documentation of data into databases.
- Data verification and auditing of outliers.
- Preserve the company's records and manage paperwork effectively.

## **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

ASSOCIATES OF SCIENCE (A.S.) IN GENERAL SCIENCES, 2017

DURHAM TECHNICAL COMMUNITY COLLEGE, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN CLOUD COMPUTING, 2022

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, Utah

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS, 2019

• Cloud Practitioner

Axelos, 2020

ITIL Certified

CompTIA, 2020

- CompTIA Security+ Certified
- CompTIA Network+ Certified
- CompTIA A+ Certified
- CompTIA Project+ Certified
- CompTIA Pentest+ Certification Pending

ISC2, 2023

• Certified in Cybersecurity

Linux Professional Institute, 2020

Linux Essentials

DIEGO CASTILLO Page 3

### Microsoft, 2017 - 2022

- Microsoft Azure Administrator
- Microsoft Azure AI fundamentals
- Microsoft Identity and Access Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Information Protections Administrator Associate
- MTA Software Development Fundamentals

### Python Institute, 2022

• Certified Associate in Python Programming

### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

MITRE ATT&CK WGU Association Durham Technical Alumni Association Axelos

## **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

- Office 365 Administration: Security and Compliance Center, Exchange Administration, Azure AD
- Windows 10 and Server: Domain Controller management, Active Directory, PowerShell scripting
- Switches/Routers/Firewalls: DHCP setup and scope, wired and wireless network configuration, Firewall Rules/Zones/VPN setup
- Documentation and Ticketing: Contributing to IT knowledgebase, Physical and Logical diagramming.
- Troubleshooting: Remote deployment and domain additions, Troubleshoot client home equipment.
- Creation of Webserver and load balancing; Microsoft (IIS)
- Penetration Tools: Wireshark, Metasploit, Nmap, Python scripting.
- SSO Creation across many applications

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

**Interests:** Competition in Brazilian jiu-jitsu and Judo. Penetration Testing. Business and stocks. Being active with my dogs and Wife.